Guide to the Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 Records, 1836-1975 AIS.1991.08
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 Records
1836-1975
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1991.08
80 Linear Feet (44 boxes and 21 oversize items)
Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 is the oldest continually existing labor union in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. The Pittsburgh union was one of the fourteen founding locals of the International Typographical Union (ITU) in 1852. This collection contains meeting minutes, dues ledgers, publications and correspondence from Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James C. Lowen, President of Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7, in 1991.
History
Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 can trace its history back to the Journeymen Printers of Pittsburgh, which was founded in 1836. It is the oldest continually existing labor union in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. The Pittsburgh union was one of the fourteen founding locals of the International Typographical Union (ITU) in 1852. Newspapers resisted the unionization of printers, resulting in several strikes. Workers who broke the strike were blacklisted by the union and called "rats." Union shops, or "chapels" in the union's terminology, were also the subject of strikes when they did not adhere to their agreement with the union or hired non-union printers all of which appear in the rat book. The ITU was a powerful early member of the American Federation of Labor and was ejected from the AFL as part of the Committee for Industrial Organization in 1938. The ITU rejoined the AFL in 1944 under the condition of autonomy. In 1986, the local affiliated with the Communication Workers of America to form its Printing, Publishing, and Media Workers Sector. Even though the Pittsburgh local was designated the number CWA 14827, it is still known as Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7.
Previous Citation
Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 Records, 1836-1975, AIS.1991.08, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains meeting minutes, dues ledgers and correspondence from Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7. Also present is financial information of the local union and publications of the Typographical Union. The local union by-laws and information regarding strikes are also included.
Separated Material
Oversize materials can be found in Range 1/12/3 and in map-case 3 drawer 12.
Related Material
100 Years as a Chartered Union, 1852-1952: History of Pittsburgh Typographical Union No.7, International Typographical Union and Pittsburgh Central Labor Union by John A. Feigel, 1952.
Allegheny County Labor Council Records, 1939-1998, AIS.1997.28, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into seven series as follows:
Series I. Minutes
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Publications
Series IV. Finances
Series V. Membership
Series VI. Contracts and Arbitration
Series VII. Officer and Committee Reports
Membership lists; Ledgers (Account books); Typists -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor disputes -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor; Collective labor agreements -- Printing industry -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Periodicals; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Minute books; Clark, William B.; International Typographical Union; Woodmansee, Howard L.; Riefer, Franklin A.; Bloomington, Maurice; Dabney, George R.; Klinger, William A.; Feigel, John A.; Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Minutes, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains minute books for Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 and its various chapels within it dating from 1867 to1967. Minutes from organizations such as the Allied Printing Trades Council and the Pittsburgh Union Label Council from 1936 to 1959 are also included. Within the minute books are descriptions of the issues discussed at each meeting as well as various treasury and committee reports.
  - Minute Books, 1867-1902 (Box 1, Volume 1-8)
  - Minute Books, 1903-1921 (Box 2, Volume 1-5)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1921-1938 (Box 3, Volume 1-3)
  - Allied Printing Trade Council Minutes, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Joint Union Committee Minutes, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Allied Printing Trades Council Minutes, 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minute Book, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Volume 4)
  - Allied Printing Trades Council Minutes, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Allied Printing Trades Council Minutes, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Union Label Council Minutes, November 1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minute Book for the Union Printers Association, 1909-1952 (Box 3, Volume 5)
  - Mass Transportation Committee Meeting Minutes, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Urban League of Pittsburgh Executive Board Minutes, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, June 25, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, November 1952 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, March 25, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, April 22, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, January 27, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, March 24, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Board of Public Education Minutes, December 3, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, February 23, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - MInutes of the14th Regular Meeting of the Greater Pittsburgh Airport Advisory Committee, February 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council Minutes, March 23, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Minutes of the 17th Regular Meeting of the Greater Pittsburgh Airport Advisory Committee, September 1955 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Board of Public Education Meeting Minutes, December 20, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - The Board of Public Education Meeting Minutes, April 24, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of the 23rd Regular Meeting of the Greater Pittsburgh Airport Advisory Committee, September 2, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The Board of Public Education Meeting Minutes, Septmeber 18, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Allied Printing Trades Council Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Chapel Minute Book, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Volume 6)
  - Minute Books, 1867-1934 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 1-3)
  - Minute Book and Dues Report Ledger, 1934-1938 (Oversize 1)
  - Minute Book, 1934-1939 (Oversize 2)
- Correspondence, II.
  This series contains the correspondence of the Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 from 1899 to 1902 and from 1927 to 1976. These letters range from brief to comprehensive, and contain information regarding both personal and business matters. These letters represent incoming and outgoing messages of various officials, members, and committees within Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7. The series is broken into six subseries arranged by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 presidential terms.
  - William A. Klinger, 1899-1900; 1.
    Contained within this subseries are the correspondence received and sent by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the presidency of William A. Klinger from 1899 to 1900. These letters include business matters pertaining to various union strikes and controversies. The majority of communications in this subseries are incoming correspondence from other unions to Klinger pledging their support to Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the strike of 1900. Also included in this subseries are letters to various officers, including the Vice-President and Secretary of Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7.
    - Controversy between Local Union No. 7 and Union No. 20, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Broomakers Union Correspondence, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Circular Letter to President Klinger, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Machinists Controversy Correspondence, 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Strike Correspondence, 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Strike Support, 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence of President Klinger, 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with the International Typographical Union, 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Labor Spy Letter, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - George R. Dabney, 1902; 2.
    Contained within this subseries are the correspondence received and sent by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the presidency of George R. Dabney in 1902. These letters are the business correspondence of Secretary Edward E. Paget from March to December of 1902.
    - Secretary Edward E. Padget Correspondence, March-December 1902 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Maurice Bloomington, 1926-1927; 3.
    Contained within this subseries are the correspondence received and sent by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the presidency of Maurice Bloomington from 1926 to 1927. This subseries includes incoming and outing correspondence regarding business matters of not only President Bloomington, but also other officers and members of the Pittsburgh union local.
    - Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Franklin A. Riefer, 1928; 4.
    Contained within this subseries are the correspondence received and sent by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the presidency of Franklin A. Riefer from 1928. The letters include those written and received by Riefer regarding personal and business matters. Also present are letters written and received by William B. Clark secretary of Pittsburgh No. 7.
    - William B. Clark and Franklin A. Riefer Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Howard L. Woodmansee, 1929-1936; 5.
    Contained within this subseries are the correspondence received and sent by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the presidency of Howard L. Woodmansee from 1929 to 1936. These letters detail the business matters Woodmansee confronted during his term, including a large number of job scale correspondence received by the President from 1933 to 1935. Other letters are incoming and outgoing to officers of Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7. The correspondence of the locals' secretaries, William B. Clark from 1930 to 1934 and George Bradley from 1934 to 1937, are also present.
    - Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with the International Typo. Union, 1929-1932 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - William B. Clark Correspondence, 1930-1934 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Job Scale Correspondence of H.L. Woodmansee, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence with the International Typo. Union, 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence of George Bradley, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - President H.L. Woodmansee Correspondence, 1931-1937 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - John A. Feigel, 1937-1976; 6.
    Contained within this subseries are the correspondence received and sent by Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 during the presidency of John A. Fiegel, dating from 1937 to 1976. The majority of letters in this subseries are the incoming and outgoing correspondence of Fiegel. The correspondence includes some personal and a large number of business matters, with letters to and from the other officers of Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7, the International Typographical Union, and several other Pittsburgh unions, as well as the Apprentice, Union Label, and Joint Standing Committees. Also included are a large number of communications of the Secretary and the Secretary-Treasurers from 1949 to 1956. The correspondence of Secretary George Bradley, dating from 1938 to 1942 and 1949 to 1950, are contained in this series as well.
    - Apprenticeship Committee Correspondence, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence of George Bradley, 1938-1942 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Outgoing Correspondence of President Feigel, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Outgoing Correspondence of President Feigel, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Incoming Correspondence of President Feigel, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Incoming Correspondence of President Feigel, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    - Incoming Correspondence of President Feigel, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence of International Typo. Union President Baker, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence of International Typo. Union Preseident Baker, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - International Typographical Union Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Secretary-Treasurer of the International Typo. Union Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence of International Typo. Union President Baker, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Apprentice Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - President Randolph's Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Westinghouse Valley Printing Company, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - International Typographical Union Correspondence, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence of Vice-President Brown, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence of President Randolph, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Secretary's Correspondence, October 16, 1946-December 30, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence of International Typo. Union Secretary-Treasurer Taylor-Hurd, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence of President Feigel, 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence of Secretary's Office, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence of Secretary's Office, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of President Feigel, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence of Pittsburgh Central Labor League, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Secretary-Treasurer's Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Will of George Bradley, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence of President Feigel, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Seretary and Secretary-Treasurer's Correspondence, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Secretary and Secretary-Treasurer's Correspondence, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Secretary and Secretary-Treasurer's Correspondence, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Secretary and Secretary-Treasurer's Correspondence, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Secretary-Treasurer Hurd's Correspondence, 1947-1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Union Matters, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Union Matters, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence of Heart Association, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Union Matters, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Union Label Committee Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - R.I.D.C Correspondence, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence of President Feigel, 1951-1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - United Fund Correspondence of President Feigel, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - President Feigel's Corresondence with the International Typo. Union, 1946-1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - President Feigel's Correspondence with the International Typo. Union, 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of President Feigel from Roosevelt Hotel, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - President Feigel's ACTION HOUSING Correspondence, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence of Pittsburgh Newspaper Council, 1942-1958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - President Feigel's Correspondence, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Health and Welfare Association Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
    - The Board of Public Education Correspondence Materials, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
    - School Board Correspondence to President Feigel, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Airport Advisory Committee Correspondence, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Board of Public School Education Correspondence, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Publications, III.
  This series contains publications concerning the Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 from 1915 to 1959. The majority of these publications are the monthly bulletins of the International Typographical Union and Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7. Contained in the series are also monthly issues of the Typographical Journal from 1915 to 1959 published by the International Typographical Union. Also present are many pamphlets and booklets written by various labor union figures or organizations concerning labor and union issues.
  - The Official Bulletin of the International Typographical Union, 1915-1933 (Box 11, Volume 1-19)
  - The Official Bulletin of the International Typographical Union, 1934-1949 (Box 12, Volume 1-22)
  - The Official Bulletin of the International Typographical Union, 1950-1957 (Box 13, Volume 1-8)
  - Book of Laws of the International Typographical Union, 1929-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1-15)
  - Pittsburgh Typographical Union No. 7 Official Bulletin, 1930-1958 (Box 14, Folder 1-23)
  - The Typographical Journal of the International Typographical Union, 1915-1931 (Box 15, Folder 1-42)
  - The Typographical Journal of the International Typographical Union, 1931-1936 (Box 16, Folder 1-30)
  - The Typographical Journal of the International Typographical Union, 1936-1940 (Box 17, Folder 1-25)
  - The Typographical Journal of the International Typographical Union, 1940-1946 (Box 18, Folder 1-38)
  - The Typographical Journal of the International Typographical Union, 1946-1959 (Box 19, Folder 1-41)
  - Cushing's Manual: Rules of Proceedings and Debate in Deliberative Assemblies by Luther S. Cushing, 1887 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Closed Union Shop is Justifiable: The Case for a Closed Union Shop by Edison L. Bowers and Alfred G. Buehler, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - A Pictorial Presentation of the Union Printers Home, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - A Handbook for Committeemen of Local Lodges of S.W.O.C. by Steel Workers Organizing Committee, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Collective Bargaining by R.D. Bundy, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - The Newspaper Credo of William Randolph Hearst, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - The Closed Shop by the National Association of Manufacturers, December 2, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, May 2, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Tuberculosis League of Pittsburgh Activities, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - The Veteran's Guide: What You Are Entitled To, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - The Arbitration Journal by the American Arbitration Association, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - How to Arbitrate a Labor Dispute by Theodore W. Kheel, June 1946 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Guide to the National Labor Realtions Act: Procedures and Practices by Louis G. Silverberg, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - New Labor Law: Management Relations Act with Explanation, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Programs for the 90th Anniversary, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - A Political Challenge to Business and Industry by Henry Ford II, April 1949 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - What's Wrong with the T-H Law...Plenty by the American Federation of Labor, June 1949 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - The Gazette: Pennsylvania is the Keystone of the Democratic Arch, October 12, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Samuel Gompers Credo: Qoutations from his Speeches and Writings, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - International Typographical Union Manuals, 1949-1951 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Official Civil Defense Publications by the Plant and Security Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Growing Pains in the Suburbs: The Story of Metropolitan Pittsburgh's Building Boom by The Pittsburgh Press, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Brief History of the American Labor Movement by Maurice J. Tobin and Ewan Clague, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Letter Press Printing by the Anglo-American Council on Productivity, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - American Federation of Labor Publications, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Pennsylvania Week News Bulletin by the Department of Commerce of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Carnegie Magazine, September 1952 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Pittsburgh Renaissance Issue by the Pittsburgh Press, December 13, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - 'Right-to-Work' Laws: Three Moral Studies by an Oblate Father, an Eminent Rabbi, and a Methodist Dean, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Decision: The Graduate Guide to Business by Oliver P. Bardes, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Policy Resolutions of the AFL-CIO, January 1955 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Constitution of the AFL-CIO and other Official Documents Relating to the Achievement of Labor Unity, January 1956 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - The Tocsin by the International Typographical Union, April 1957 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - The Present Committee on Education Beyond High School: Second Report to the President, July 1957 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - 29 Timely Mailing Tips: To Help You Get More for Your Postage Dollar by the U.S. Postal Service, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - International Stablility and Progress; US Interests and Instruments by the American Assembly, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - United States Department of Labor Publications, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Pennsylvania Housing: Report on the Governor's Citizens Committee on Housing, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - The Science Press: "Foremost in Cold-Type Composition", 1957 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Wages and the Public Interest by the Conference on Economic Progress, January 1958 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Syngman Rhee: An Asian Leader Speaks for Peace by the American-Asian Educational Exchange, January 1958 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Breaking Through the Age Barrier by the Bureau of Asian Security, May 1958 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - How Old is Top Management in Insurance? by Theodore Bakerman, May 1958 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - AFL-CIO Education News and Views, November 1958 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Harvard Business Review: the Magazine for Thoughtful Businessmen, November-December 1958 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - The Metropolitan Area as a Racial Problem by Morton Grodzins, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - The Challenge: Highlights of the Pennsylvania Department of Public Welfare's Programs and Plans, November- December 1958 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - The Changing Economic Function of the Central City by Raymond Vernon, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - US News and World Report: What the Labor Unions Want Now, February 2, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Headline Series 'Great Decisions...1959'; Reshaping Foriegn Policy Amid Revolutions by the Foriegn Policy Association (Box 20, Folder 50)